[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "Hacker news is a link aggregator site for hackers created by?",
    "choices": [
      "Paul Ryan",
      "Paul Allen",
      "Paul Graham",
      "Paul Walker",
      "Chris Paul"
    ],
    "correctChoice": "Paul Graham",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_News' target='_blank'>If you answer this question wrong, welcome to HN!</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "What company did Show HN on Hacker news, but got some pessimistic comments, including, \"you can already build such a system yourself quite trivially\"?",
    "choices": ["Airbnb", "Box", "Coinbase", "Dropbox", "Firebase"],
    "correctChoice": "Dropbox",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863' target='_blank'>The infamous Dropbox Show HN page</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "How many karma you need to be able to downvote other comments?",
    "choices": ["1", "31", "251", "501", "You can downvote comments?"],
    "correctChoice": "501",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented#downvoting-comments' target='_blank'>One of Hacker News's undocumented feature</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "question": "What is the username of one of our moderators?",
    "choices": ["dang", "ding", "spez", "momod", "All of the above"],
    "correctChoice": "dang",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-silicon-valley/the-lonely-work-of-moderating-hacker-news' target='_blank'>A very cool and detailed article from Newyorker about HN behind the scene</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": "Which computer scientist did an AMA (ask me anything) on HN?",
    "choices": [
      "Alan Kay",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup",
      "Claude Shannon",
      "Donald Knuth",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctChoice": "Alan Kay",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11939851' target='_blank'>AMA page</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "Which of the following username isn't included in top 5 users with most karma?",
    "choices": ["tptacek", "jacquesm", "patio11", "danso", "sctb"],
    "correctChoice": "sctb",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/leaders' target='_blank'>Leaderboards of imaginary internet points</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": "What site releases a satirical weekly annotated digest of the top HN posts?",
    "choices": [
      "negationreview",
      "weeklydisjunction",
      "nvm",
      "n-gate",
      "daringfireball"
    ],
    "correctChoice": "n-gate",
    "explanation": "<a href='http://n-gate.com/' target='_blank'>One way of avoiding an echo chamber</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": "The original hacker news program is written in what programming language?",
    "choices": ["Arc", "Basic", "Clojure", "Delphi", "Typescript"],
    "correctChoice": "Arc",
    "explanation": "<a href='http://paulgraham.com/hackernews.html' target='_blank'>It is what it used to be</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "At the moment, what's the title of HN submission with highest point?",
    "choices": [
      "A Message to Our Customers",
      "Steve Jobs has passed away.",
      "Stephen Hawking has died",
      "Reflecting on one very, very strange year at Uber",
      "Show HN: HN Pop Quiz - Useless trivia quiz about HN"
    ],
    "correctChoice": "Stephen Hawking has died",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://hn.algolia.com/' target='_blank'>I wish I can update the correct answer</a>"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "What is the \"comeback of all time\" according to pg?",
    "choices": [
      "\"Did you create the company by yourself?\"",
      "\"Did you win the Putnam?\"",
      "\"Did you join ICPC?\"",
      "\"Did you got Pulitzer Prize?\"",
      "\"Did you invent this algorithm?\""
    ],
    "correctChoice": "\"Did you win the Putnam?\"",
    "explanation": "<a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35079' target='_blank'>Sorry if the question is too trivial, it's for the bell curve :)</a>"
  }
]
